SF. front-end developer

Personal Information

Stefan Frede contact [at] frede [dot] io +49-170-5434476 Ehrenbergstraße 16a Scanbox #03611 10245 Berlin, Germany

Skills

HTML and (S)CSS
Responsive Web Design
Accessibility & Progressive Enhancement
Vanilla JavaScript
Web Components, LitElement, and lit-html
Jest, Mocha, and Chai
Redux and Redux-Saga
Webpack, Git, and Continuous Integration
Docker

Personal Statement

I'm a front-end developer with a focus on HTML, CSS, Accessibility and Progressive Enhancement. I specialize in reducing the complexity of modern "best practices" and like to limit myself to browser APIs when using JavaScript. I have been working in this business since 2004.

Professional Experience (extract)

February 2020 – present

T-Systems Multimedia Solutions GmbH | Freelance

• Built accessible components for a Salesforce application.

October 2019 - present

Schweisthal Beschlag- und Schließtechnik GmbH | Freelance

· Built a web app to configure a locking system.

July 2019 - present

Aboutbooks GmbH | Freelance

· Built promotions from publishers for new books.

November 2010 - present

50plus-Treff GmbH | Freelance

- \bullet Implemented the redesign to make the website mobile-friendly.
- · Maintained the website and implemented change requests.

July 2017 - September 2019

ARIGO Software GmbH | Freelance

- · Built and maintained Web Components.
- Built an interface to communicate via a WebSocket connection with a REST API

November 2016 - Juni 2018

tracdelight GmbH | Freelance

· Built and maintained brand promotions.

November 2005 - July 2017

Experteer GmbH | Freelance

- Built and maintained the web site.
- · Built inhouse tools.
- Implemented code standards.

Education

Macromedia - Akademie für neue Medien | 2001-2003

Digital Media Designer,